

Nabeel Sohail

iOS Developer

Phone: 03044841220

Address: plot 4,5 new canal park taj Bagh Lahore

Email: abdullah6236a@gmail.com

iOS developer with more than 3 years of experience in developing native iOS apps. Veteran of navigating development and submission processes. Adept at verifying compliance with both App Store policies and design best practices. I've spent the bulk of my career building iOS applications from an idea to a version 1.0 (or MVP) launch for clients and small startups which turned into great products with thousands of users.

EXPERIENCE

3S solutions

January 2021 - Present

Senior iOS Developer

- · Working on enterprise level apps like Orbis, responsible for maintaining and working on new features of the app
- Develop app architecture and responsible for high quality code and refactoring of the huge chunks of the product
- · Playing a key role in developing new features and working with new technologies like AWS services, Firebase

Broadstone Technologies

Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

Senior iOS Developer

- Responsible for making ARKIT apps and AI based apps, worked on large scale products like My Beauty Advisor and Locus AR
- Responsible for making MVP and maintaining different products for different features in ARKIT technology

Logicon February 2019 to July 2020

iOS Developer

- · Played a key role in developing different mvp from scratch with team of developers
- Developed key features of the applications like stripe, firebase realtime chat, firebase cloud messaging, Twilio, Video Call,
 Audio Call
- Responsible for making documentations and integrating REST APIS and key functionalities using technologies like MLKIT, AVFoundation, UIKIT, Core Data
- · Responsible for designing better app architecture and improve codebase with optimised code

VU Software Solutions

October 2017 to December 2018

iOS Developer

- Responsible for making iOS products from scratch and give support to different products
- Identify, prioritize and execute tasks in the software development life cycle
- Develop apps and integrated key features with REST APIS JSON and different technologies
- Led the discovery phase of medium to large projects to come up with a high-level design

EDUCATION

Punjab College April 2011 to February 2013

I.C.S

• Studied computer science as major, Worked on C++ and C as basic foundational skills for programming

Virtual University March 2014 to April 2017

BSCS

- Studied OOP, Data structure, Operating systems, Programming fundamentals
- Specialisation in mobile application development iOS

SKILLS

JIRA, Bitbucket, Swift, CoreData, TwilioChat, Firebase realtime database, Firebase Cloud messaging, Apple push notification

service, OOP, AVFoundation, Cocoa touch, UIKIT, Google MLKIT, GIT, Stripe, Trello, MVC, Design Patterns, GCD Concurrency, Memory Management, 3rd party SDKs and API(S) integration, MVVM, SWIFTUI, Combine Reactive Framework, Asana, Augmented Reality, SQL and RDBMS, Agile Development Methodology, Kanban

PROJECTS

VCLUB

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/v-club-promoter/id1480195539?ls=1

- This app is use to create live contest for models, The voters can participate to vote their favrt model and end the contest by choosing the winner with the rating
- The Models can participate through the app and communicate with the organisers, This is a complete platform for models to reach different organisations and brands

Amplifyd

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/amplifyd/id1465702628

- Amplifyd is an app for digital marketing platform for brands and influencers, Where brand can hire influencers and make contract to market their products, Integrate local and push notifications for users
- Influencers and brands can communicate with each other, App uses instagram live stats of influencers to help brand narrow down their relevant respective influencers to hire

EmergencMe

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id1148985518

- Created an app for client for emergency and alerts App features safety network chat messages communication with firebase live App uses firebase to store data and realtime database
- One of the most interesting feature of application is to alert users in their safety group whenever there is an emergency, EmergenceMe provide users to create alerts with push notifications to notify other users

Bitmal

- Bitmal was an app for cryptocurrency the main features of the app was to provide organizations the facility to create projects and find volunteers from different parts of the world for their work
- App uses stripe with apple pay to make transactions, Created live chat integration with realtime firebase database

My Beauty Advisor

https://apps.apple.com/ie/app/my-beauty-advisor/id1518493327

- My beauty advisor uses AI tech to show products on your face, The app uses apple's new augmented reality kit
- The app also uses google's MLKIT as a feature to try different products on your face specially for the phones which doesn't have ARKIT technology
- The most useful features of the app is to assist user in finding good products by simulating them on face and help user to pick and choose the products which suits them

GLF Locker

https://apps.apple.com/qb/app/qlf-locker/id968257062

- GLF. Locker is an innovative platform that is a one stop shop for golf coaching. The platform covers the business end, provides all the tools required for a Coach through to giving the Student a great experience while they are striving to achieve their goals.
- Students can attend lessons, keep track of their classes and their progress understand the game through different coaches by taking classes and lessons,
- · Coach can recommend videos teach students and give them an organised schedule for learning process
- Worked on AWS services, integrated firebase for different functionalities, Worked on videos audio uploading through AWS files uploading and graphs
- · Created live chats, group chats, media module, connect module and other bulk of features for the product

Rebounder March 2021 to Present

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/mr-rebounder/id1300713793

- Mr Rebounder an exercise based app use to burn calories, which collects data from your apple watch and BLE device to show you your workout details and manage your workout plan.
- The app uses apple watch and BLE device to collect the data, App uses ARKIT Technology to show workouts, In app purchases for users to purchase premium exercises.

VOMobile Presently Working

• This is a platform use by office to share files between employees clients and different departments, User can share large amount of files documents images through this portal

- Different features provided for the user like Chat, Conversation through which user can make groups and communicate with the desired department, clients or employees and share documents with them
- Different technologies are used in achieving the Chat or Conversation Functionality, Sockets, SignalR, Combine Framework, FCM used to achieve features